Jordan Moore

💌 jordanmoore753@gmail.com 👂 Croton-on-Hudson, NY 🤘 https://jordanmoore.dev/

Profile

Software engineer with experience building fast, scalable cloud applications. Experience with JavaScript, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Docker, Rails, and React. Former educator and M.Ed.

Skills

Backend Node.js, Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL, GraphQL & RESTful APIs, Docker

Frontend

JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, jQuery

Tooling

Git, Linux, Pivotal Tracker

Cloud

Digital Ocean, Heroku, Google Cloud Platform

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Satellite

2020 - present

https://satellite-baas.github.io/

Satellite is a multi-instance backend-as-a-service (BaaS) that provides the essential features of data persistence, frontend hosting, and a GraphQL API without the complexities of managing and configuring servers. Built with Node.js, Express, Kubernetes, Docker, React, and DGraph.

- Worked with a remote team to create Satellite infrastructure
- Co-built Satellite core application for a single backend
- Created methods for performing health and status checks
- Designed the Admin GUI for managing and deploying Satellites using React
- Integrated the Admin GUI with Satellite and the Kubernetes cluster
- Contributed to architectural decisions regarding Satellite's multi-instance infrastructure
- Co-authored technical case study, detailing Satellite's design and implementation

Full Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2019 - 2020

Remote. Built open-source projects using Ruby, JavaScript, Node. is, SQL, React, HTML/CSS, and Express.

- DS-Plus: an NPM package built with JavaScript that provides fast, non-native data structures
- Regexer: a Regex editor that evaluates Ruby and JavaScript expressions, built with React and Ruby
- Mello: a Trello clone built in React and Redux with a Rails API backend that supports creating, editing, and deletingboards, lists, and cards

Educator, Various Districts

2014 - 2018

Subjects taught: Web Development, Mathematics, AP Psychology, US History

Education

Launch School 2019 - 2020

Multi-year Software Engineering curriculum focused on mastering web development fundamentals https://launchschool.com/employers

Roberts Wesleyan College, M.Ed Childhood Education

2013 - 2014

State University of New York at Geneseo, BA Philosophy

2010 - 2013